Something strange is coming to their planet...Us!
Planet 51 is a animation, family, comedy film directed by Jorge Blanco.
When Earth astronaut Capt.
Chuck Baker arrives on Planet 51 -- a world reminiscent of American suburbia circa 1950 -- he tries to avoid capture,
recover his spaceship and make it home safely, all with the help of an empathetic little green being.
Capt. Charles 'Chuck' Baker (voice), played by Dwayne Johnson.
Skiff (voice), played by Seann William Scott.
Neera (voice), played by Jessica Biel.
Lem / Rover (voice), played by Justin Long.
General Grawl (voice), played by Gary Oldman.
Professor Kipple (voice), played by John Cleese.
Planet 51 is a 2009 Spanish-British-American animated science fiction comedy
film directed by Jorge Blanco from a script by Joe Stillman.
Starring the voices of Dwayne Johnson, Justin Long, Jessica Biel, Gary Oldman, Seann William Scott, John Cleese and Freddie Benedict, the film
follows an astronaut who lands on an alien planet, as one of the aliens helps him return to his ship while evading the military.
An international co-production between Spain, the United Kingdom, and the United States, the film was originally
acquired for North American distribution by New Line Cinema, but then sold to Sony Pictures before completion.
Originally titled Planet One, and later named as an allusion to Area 51, the film was completed on a $70
million budget, which, at the time of its release, was the most expensive film produced in Spain.
Planet 51 was released on 20 November 2009, in the United States and Canada by Sony Pictures Releasing's TriStar Pictures and Remstar Media Partners
respectively, on 27 November in Spain by DeAPlaneta Distribución, and 4 December in the United Kingdom by HandMade Films International.
The film grossed $105.6 million in the worldwide box office.
While the film was well received in Spain, earning a Goya Award for Best Animated
Film, it received generally negative reviews from American critics.
The film explores themes of spacecraft, flying saucer,
alien life-form, alien, alien planet.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.